MONICA:
Hey, hon?
Would you help me
get the plates down?
Yeah. Hey,
here's an idea.
Why don't we use
our wedding china today?
No. I think we should
save our china
for something really special.
Like... if the Queen
of England comes over.
Honey, she keeps canceling
on us.
Take the hint.
What... what if something
gets broken?
They're so expensive.
What is the point
of having them if
we never use them?
Okay, but if something
gets broken
and then the Queen
comes over...
I will explain it to her.
Oh, yeah. Like I'm going
to let you talk to the Queen.
Wow, the parade is really good
this year.
Man, those horses can crap.
TV ANNOUNCER:
Next up is a marching band
from Muskogee, Oklahoma.
Muskogee? That's, like,
four hours from Tulsa!
Whoo-hoo!
ANNOUNCER:
And here comes the float
with the stars
of the popular daytime soap
Days of Our Lives.
Oh, my God!
Aren't you one
of the stars
of the popular daytime
soap Days of Our Lives?
Yeah!
I totally forgot,
I'm supposed to be there.
I can't believe I forgot.
I usually write stuff
like this down on my arm.
Oh!
Stupid long sleeves!
What are you going to do?
I guess I'm going
to have to come up
with a really good reason
why I wasn't there.
The producers are going
to be so mad at me.
They sat us all down yesterday
and said, "Everyone has
to be there 6:00 a.m. sharp.
That means you, Tribbiani."
Like... like I was
some kind of idiot.
Well, you proved
them wrong.
Yeah.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ When the rain starts to pour ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ Like I've been there before ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Oh, Emma.
This is your first
Thanksgiving.
What are you thankful for?
Mommy's boobies?
A lot of people are
thankful for those.
( knocking on door )
WOMAN:
Hello? Rachel?
Who is it?
It's your
favorite sister.
Jill?
Amy.
Hide my rings.
( groans )
Amy!
Happy Thanksgiving.
Do you have a hair straightener?
Um... hi.
Oh.
Aw...
Hi...
Hair straightener.
( chuckles )
I haven't see you
in, like, a year.
Oh, I know, I know.
I've just been crazed.
Oh, well, yeah, me, too.
Um, I had a baby.
I decorated Dad's office.
Oh, yeah?
Well, unless you pushed
a desk out of your vagina
not the same thing.
Listen, um, about that
hair straightener, honey
I really need one--
I'm going to have dinner
at my boyfriend's house.
Oh, my God.
Mm-hmm.
Is this Emmet?
Uh, it's Emma.
It's a girl?
Hey, Amy.
Oh, Amy, you
remember Ross.
Uh... not really.
But... you are much cuter than
that geeky guy she used to date.
That was me.
No.
He was this creepy guy
from high school
who had this huge crush on her
since, like,
the ninth grade.
Still me.
No, I'm not talking about you.
Come on, it was
your fat friend's brother
with that bad afro,
do you remember?
Okay, Amy, I'm going to save you
some time, okay?
All me.
Careful.
Careful! Sorry.
I'll tell you what.
For the rest of our lives
I'll be careful
until told otherwise.
Wait a minute, this isn't
the china we picked out.
I know.
After you left the store,
I chose different ones.
Why?
Well, no offense, honey
but your taste is
a little feminine for me.
Oh, suddenly flowers
are feminine?
Hey, everybody!
Happy Thanksgiving.
Hey, happy Thanksgiving.
Pheebs...
Hey, what's going on, Joe?
I-I-I need a good lie.
Oh. Okay.
How about the whole "man walking
on the Moon" thing, you know?
You-you could... you could
see the strings, people.
No, no, no. I need
a good lie to explain
why I wasn't at a
work thing today.
Ooh, honey,
you stink at lying.
I do not.
Oh, really? Okay,
let me ask you something.
Yesterday at the coffee house
I went to the bathroom,
and when I came back
my muffin was gone--
who took it?
Somebody opened the door
to the coffee house
and a raccoon
came running in
and went straight
for your muffin.
I said, "Hey, don't eat
that-- that's Phoebe's."
And he said...
He said, "Joey,
you stink at lying."
What am I going to do?
Don't worry, don't worry.
We'll come up
with a good lie.
I'll help you practice it.
Oh, great, that'd
be great. Thank you.
Sure. What-what was
the work thing?
Uh...
"Pick up Grandma
at the airport"?
Oh, man...
Oh, she's precious.
Do you ever worry that she's
going to get your real nose?
Amy...
Yes, I do.
I really do.
( cell phone rings )
Hello?
Yeah. Um, hang on one sec.
Can I take this upstairs?
Sure.
We don't live there, but...
AMY:
Seriously?
It's-it's just these rooms?
I thought you were a doctor.
Yeah, no, Ross has a PhD.
Ew.
God, she is unbelievable.
I know. I mean,
a PhD is just as good as an MD.
Oh, sure, Ross, yeah.
If I have a heart attack
in a restaurant
I want you there
with your fossil brush.
Stupid Thanksgiving.
What? What?
What happened?
My boyfriend canceled on me.
I mean, I... I finally find
a real relationship
I mean, someone that I
can spend this day with
and then his wife
comes back into town.
I swear, it's almost
not even worth dating
married guys.
Don't say that.
Oh, I was so looking forward
to this.
It was going to be
such a beautiful Thanksgiving.
( sobbing ):
We were going to have sushi.
Oh, Amy, don't cry.
Um... Ross, could I talk
to you in private?
Sure. You want
to go upstairs?
Um...
look, I was thinking,
if it's okay with Monica
I would like to invite Amy
to Thanksgiving.
You know, I think
that's a great idea.
It'll be like the
pilgrims bringing
the Indians syphilis.
Look, I know she's
a little tough to take...
( groans )
but she has nowhere else to go
and she's my sister, all right?
And she's Emma's aunt.
And I would like them to bond.
Okay, fine, but
I don't want them
bonding too much.
I don't want her telling
Emma she needs a nose job.
Ross, you know what?
She may need one.
We're just going to have
to make our peace with that!
( sighs )
Hi.
Hey.
Hey, you guys.
This is my sister Amy.
This is Chandler, Joey, Phoebe,
and you know Mon.
Hi.
Oh, my God.
You're on Days of Our Lives.
( chuckles ):
Yeah.
Wow.
They must put
a lot of makeup on you.
Hap-Hap-Happy Thanksgiving.
Hey.
Hi.
Hi, you.
So, welcome.
Is this the first time
you're seeing Emma?
Yeah, I-I think so.
It's nice to meet you, Emma.
Phoebe.
Oh. That's a funny noise.
I still need
some help here.
Oh, right. Okay, um...
Okay, so it's not just
the lie you tell
but it's the way you tell it.
For example, if you
look down at the ground
when you're talking
people know you're lying.
Oh. I don't why this
is so hard for me.
You know, I mean, lying
is basically just acting
and I am a terrific actor.
You are a terrific actor.
Hey.
Where's the baby?
Oh, we just put her
down for her nap.
Listen,
I was just thinking.
You know what
would be incredible?
If you guys died.
Thank you, Amy.
No, no,
then I would get the baby.
I mean, you know,
it would be just like a movie.
Like, at first, I wouldn't know
what to do with her
and then I would rise
to the occasion
and then-then I'd get a makeover
and then I'd get married.
That's a great movie!
Now, listen, not that you guys
could stop me or anything
'cause, you know,
you'd be dead, but...
I was thinking about
changing her name.
I'm just not really
a big fan of Emily.
Emma.
Emma, Ross wants you.
Phoebe!
Why does she keep making
that noise?
Honey, I don't know
how to tell you this
but, um, if something
were to happen to
Ross or myself...
um, you wouldn't
get the baby.
Well, who would?
Well, we haven't officially
asked them yet
but we would want
Monica and Chandler.
I can't believe you'd
want us to raise Emma.
Yeah, oh, my God,
I'm so moved.
I don't believe this.
Hold on a second.
You guys die,
and I don't get your baby?
Look, Amy, see,
we're a lot closer to
Monica and Chandler.
We see them every day,
and truthfully, honey
you don't seem very
connected to the baby.
Connected? I mean... to what?
She's a lump.
You know, guys,
I got to say
this means
so much to me.
I mean, that you would
trust me with your child.
I mean, we all know
that Monica and I
have been trying to have
a baby of our own, and...
you know, I've
had my doubts
about my skills
as a father, but...
that you two...
This guy?
Seriously?
Okay!
It's time for dinner.
Everyone, we're using
our fancy china
and it's very expensive,
so please be careful.
Whoa.
Whoa...
Okay, just to be clear--
comedy with the plates
will not be well received.
Hey.
How come my plate's
less fancy than
everyone else's?
Do you not trust me
with a fancy plate?
No, honey, that's
a special plate.
See, it's a game.
Whoever gets
that plate wins.
I can't believe I won.
This is such a slap in the face.
I mean, I'm your sister
and you would give your baby
to these strangers over me.
Monica is
Ross's sister.
No, Ross's sister
was really fat.
That was me.
No, she was this really
dorky girl in high school
used to follow Rachel around
like a puppy dog.
Amy! You've got
to stop doing that.
Okay, uh, listen,
I know that you're having
a little bit
of a family crisis
but you don't have
to take it out on the plates.
In fact, I think
that everyone
should cut their
food like this.
Now, see?
This way, you protect the plates
and, let's face it,
you have fun.
Okay, how
about this?
If you guys die
and the crazy
plate lady dies...
then do I get the baby?
No, if crazy plate la...
If Monica dies
then I would get Emma, right?
Well, actually...
Actually what?
Uh... It's just
that in that case
then, um... Emma
would go to my parents.
What?
Hurts, doesn't it?
Uh...
Who has to die
for me to get her?
So, if Monica's
not around
I'm not good enough
to raise Emma?
No, that, that is
not what we're saying.
Yeah, he's lying.
He looked down.
Well, what is
wrong with me?
Am I incompetent?
Because I managed to survive
whatever it is
that killed the three of you.
You're taking this
the wrong way.
We think you are going
to be a wonderful parent.
It's just, you're
more the, you know "fun" parent.
Yeah, and we'd
want to make sure
Emma has someone like Monica,
who's more of a disciplinarian
someone who can be
firm and strict.
That's not how
you see me, is it?
No, you're
all about the fun.
Look, I may not know
a lot about babies
but do you really think
I'm not capable?
No, you both are
equally capable.
It's just, you're strongest
when you're together.
Okay, so if
we both had Emma
and I died...
( knocks on table )
she'd have to give her up.
Sure. Monica would have
to give her up.
I lie better than that, right?
So let me get
this straight.
So my two friends die,
I get Emma.
Then my wife dies,
then Emma--
the one tiny ray
of hope left in my life--
gets taken away from me?
There's your movie.
Hey.
There you are.
You disappeared
after dinner.
Oh, did somebody
miss me?
Is there a child
to raise poorly?
Ross and Rachel
don't know what
they're talking about.
I mean, it's not like
they're so responsible.
Emma is the product
of a bottle of merlot
and a five-year-old condom.
Yeah, but they're right.
I'm not a strong
father figure
and I never will be.
No, you learn
these things.
You grow into it.
Yeah, but it's not
who I am, you know.
Everything they said
is exactly why I was worried
about having a kid--
and it's true
and, look, everybody knows it.
I don't know it.
I want to have
a kid with you
because I think
you're going
to be an amazing dad
at the fun parts and
at the hard parts.
Oh, yeah, well,
can you picture me saying
"Go to your room--
you're grounded."
Can you hear me say,
"You're grounded"?
You said that
to me last week.
How hard is it?
No shoes on
the furniture!
( groans )
The producer from Days
left a message
on my machine
asking why I wasn't
at the parade.
They said everybody's
pissed off at me
and they all got to meet Santa.
It's okay. I thought
of the perfect lie for you.
It's easy to remember
and it doesn't invite
a lot of questions.
You weren't at the parade
because you had
a family emergency.
Oh, I like that, yeah.
Wasn't at the parade because
I had a family emergency.
Ooh, what happened?
Uh... my sister's raccoon...
Nothing with a raccoon!
All right,
I'll take care of it.
Oh, wait, what are you doing?
Setting the table.
Yeah, we thought
it might be nice
to use the fancy china
for dessert, too.
Oh, how nice.
Maybe later we can all
go blow our noses
on my wedding dress.
Hey, dude, you okay?
Sorry about before.
Oh, no, that's okay.
You're totally right.
I don't know anything
about disciplining a child
but it did hurt
my feelings
and I want you to know
that if I die
you don't get Joey.
Uchh.
In case you
hadn't noticed
I'm not talking to you.
Uchh.
You know, this is,
this is classic Rachel.
Oh, yeah, yeah, right.
Remember in high school
when I died
and didn't give you my baby?
This might be my one chance
to have a child, Rachel.
I mean, you know
that I have been so busy
focusing on my career...
What?!
What career?!
Um... I'm a decorator.
You decorate Dad's office
and now you're a decorator?
Okay, I went
to the zoo yesterday.
Now I'm a koala bear.
Why can't you ever
be supportive?
Sup... You want
to talk supportive?
You didn't even
come and visit me
when I was in the hospital
having the baby.
Oh, yeah, well, you didn't
come to see me in the hospital
when I was getting my lips done.
Oh!
I did the first time.
Oh. Oh.
And you know what?
You want to know why
I am not giving Emily to you?
Emma.
Whose side are you on?
I'm not giving you Emma
because there is no way
you could handle
the responsibility of a child.
Well, how hard could it be?
You do it.
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo.
Do you want to know why
you don't want me
to have the baby?
Uh-huh.
Because you don't
want me to be happy.
You have always
been jealous of me.
Jealous of what?
Of your lack
of responsibility?
Your, your immaturity?
Your total disregard
for other people's feelings?
Uh, to name a few.
You know
you just, you've
always been like this.
You had to have everything
and I couldn't have anything.
Like in junior high,
when you stole Timmy from me.
I mean, do you even realize
how much that hurt me?
Timmy was my boyfriend
and you made out with him!
Oh, come on, that
was 20 years ago. Get over it.
Oh. I cannot believe it!
I cannot believe
that I invited you here today!
Yeah, well, you know
what I cannot believe?
That my so-called sister
gets a 30% discount
from Ralph Lauren
and I still have to pay retail?
Ha-ha-ha. A-ha-ha.
It's for 45.
You bitch.
You just think
you're so perfect
with your new baby
and your, your small apartment.
Well, let me tell
you something.
Your baby isn't even that cute.
Too far, Amy.
Too far.
You take that back.
No.
Take it back.
No!
What are you
going to do, make me?
Hey, man, I work out.
So do I.
I do Pilates.
I do yoga.
Bring it on!
Put the plates
back in the boxes!
Put the plates back
in the boxes!
Did you just push me?
Uh, yeah. I think I did.
All right, that's it.
Okay, forget the bubble
wrap! There isn't time!
Frizzy, frizzy,
frizzy, frizzy!
Oh, my God!
Shouldn't we stop this?!
What are you, out
of your mind?
Let's throw some
Jell-O on them.
( spitting )
Ew! Gross!
All right, that is it!
This is our apartment
and you cannot
behave this way.
Now, if you can't
act your age
then you shouldn't
be here at all.
Now, those plates
may not be as nice
as the pretty pink ones
that I picked out...
but they're very
important to Monica
and I want you to apologize
to her right now.
I'm sorry.
Mon, I'm so sorry.
Okay. That's better.
Now, I want you
to apologize to each other
and mean it.
Sorry.
By the way, that fight
was totally arousing.
Dude. Well done.
You know what?
If I die, and Rachel
dies and Monica dies
you can totally
take care of Emma.
Oh, yeah? Well, thanks.
So, so... now
do I get Joey?
Okay, but
you should know
he eats
five times a day
and shoves pennies
up his nose.
Are you okay, Mon?
Uh-huh.
I mean, these
things happen.
I mean, it's just a plate.
It's not like
somebody died.
It's all right,
you can mourn.
Thank you,
it was so beautiful.
I'm going to go to Joey's
and get the pies.
Actually, not pies.
It's just pie.
I don't care.
Oh, my God, I've lost
the will to scold.
Look, Amy.
I got a little, uh...
a little out
of control over there.
Um...
And I'm sorry.
You're my sister,
and if it really means
that much to you...
So you're going to
give me the baby?
No, I was going
to let you use
my Ralph Lauren discount.
You are not going
to regret this.
( baby crying )
Oh, she needs changing.
Oh, no, no, no.
I'll get her.
I am super-competent,
totally responsible
and fourth in line
to raise Emma.
I'll be right there, Emma.
Just let me get my trusty
diaper bag here.
Well, what do you know?
I guess I'll be the one
who dies first.
Hey, does Monica know
about her broken
plates yet?
No.
Broke them all, huh?
Yup.
You going to tell her?
Nope.
Hey.
So I'm going to put
the plates back.
You know,
I think you were right.
I don't think we should
use these plates again
for a long time.
Like only if
the queen comes?
Maybe not even then.
Hey, I did it.
I called my producer.
I told him I had
a family emergency.
He totally bought it.
Thanks for teaching me
how to lie, Pheebs.
No problem.
Next week, stealing.
'Bye, plates.
Oh, you told her
you broke all the plates, huh?
What?!
Something happened
with the plates?
Uh... yeah, this, uh...
raccoon came in...
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org